Shelby Reyes

Email: shelbyreyes90@gmail.com | Phone: 703-375-9031 | Reston, Virginia, 20190

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shelbyreyes/ | GitHub: https://github.com/sdreyes | Website: http://shelbyreyes.net/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with experience using JavaScript, React, MySQL, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, HTML5, and a variety of frameworks including Bootstrap and jQuery. Quick learner, patient teacher, and adept problem solver. Known among colleagues for keen eye for detail and superb organizational skills. Brings experience obtained through multi-faceted work environments including data-analysis, education, accounting, and customer service.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Express, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, ORMs (Sequelize, Mongoose), Appian, Photoshop, WordPress, Git. 70 WPM typing speed. High level of PC literacy.

PROJECTS

Beadli | https://github.com/sdreyes/Beadli | http://bead.li/

A MERN-stack app that allows users to create, share, and browse pixel designs intended for fuse bead crafting.

- Co-developed with a team of four, my contributions to the project largely include the implementation of user authentication, bitmap image URI creation, and dynamic rendering of data.
- MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Mongoose, Passport.js, Bitmap.js, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS3, and HTML5

Library Builder | https://google-books-sdreyes.herokuapp.com/ A MERN-stack app that allows users to search for and save books of interest through Google Books API.

MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Mongoose, Bootstrap, and Google Books API

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I - Serco - Herndon, VA

2020 - Present

Perform analysis, design, development, testing, debugging, and implementation of software applications primarily using Appian and SQL. Work on a development team using Agile Methodology and Jira. Comply with Section 508 Policy. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Completed the Appian Developer 10-Day course; please find my final project demo here
- Built multiple JavaScript webscraping solutions for exporting Appian system information into CSV format
- Enhanced external API error-handling for timeout scenarios
- Used Appian to create a Planning Poker application that we now use during each sprint planning session

Teaching Assistant – Trilogy Education Services, Penn LPS Coding Boot Camp – Philadelphia, PA **2019 - 2020**Teach students MERN stack web development skills, research and answer student questions, provide feedback on student assignments, and assist with code activities and projects. Substitute teach when the instructor is absent.

<u>Key Accomplishments</u>:

Hosted several group tutoring sessions to help students with JavaScript and Git concepts

Office Manager - Federation Early Learning Services - Broomall, PA

2015 - 2019

Design and edit marketing materials for publishing, complete weekly payroll and schedules for a team of 16 employees, coordinate community events, troubleshoot problems with and repair office equipment, and run the front desk daily *Key Accomplishments:*

- Streamlined file and data tracking for 16 employees and 60 students by creating dynamic Excel spreadsheets
- Increased student enrollment by 20% through community engagement efforts

Administrative Assistant - Michaels Stores - Springfield, PA and Woodbridge, VA **2009-2015**Maintain store funds and payroll records, prepare daily deposits, investigate money discrepancies, and audit inventory

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA – Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate, 2019 **George Mason University**, Fairfax, VA – B.A. History, 2012